ESTHER KALU

Abuja, Nigeria |kaluesther28@gmail.com |https://www.linkedin.com/in/esther-kalu |+2348020722451

PERSONAL PROFILE

A communications officer who integrates education and media to amplify humanitarian projects. I possess over 5 years of experience collaborating with private organizations, government departments and agencies, international organizations and professionals for humanitarian projects and educational solutions. My vision is to speak up for the vulnerable and raise young activists who are advocates of SDG 17, while serving as a goodwill ambassador and advocate.

SKILLS

- Cross- cultural Communication
- Organizational Success
- Content Writing
- Public Speaking
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Canva
- CapCut
- Microsoft Office

- Media Relations
- Social Media Management
- Media Programming
- Story Telling
- Interpersonal Relations
- Technical support
- News Writing
- Staff Training

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hi-impact TV/ Radio, Lagos Nigeria – Presenter, Reporter, Producer

JUL 2020 – JUL 2023

- Pitched, developed and produced video content for the Nigerian Police Force and UNICEF at the orientation workshop on "Standard Operating Procedures for Handling Cases Involving Children in Contact with the law"
- Developed and produced video content for United Nations Population Fund Youth Participatory Platform in collaboration with Lagos State Ministry of Youth and Social Development to launch the policy draft of "The Boys Charter Project"
- Produced video content on the field report of the groundbreaking ceremony of the new U.S Consulate at Eko Atlantic Lagos
- Developed and produced news headlines, newspaper review and 2 children's show "60 Seconds Game Show" and "Dandy Kids Show"
- Curated contents across 3 social media channels ensuring a cohesive online brand identity

GreenHub Africa - Volunteer Staff

JUN 2023

 Co-compere and engaged 20 secondary students to participate in 2023 World Environment Day climate action activities at UN House Abuja

Stonyhurst School Lekki, Lagos Nigeria – Educator, Playgroup Class SEPT 2018 – JUN 2020

 Developed and implemented comprehensive curriculums, tailored to address early childhood development needs and utilizing early years foundational techniques for playgroup class

Kingdom Africa TV/ Dexterity TV - Presenter, Producer, Admin Executive APR 2016 - NOV 2017

 Developed and produced news headlines for KA TV (DSTV Channel 345) and Dexterity TV (Channel 747, Free TV Abuja)

Ezinne & Sons Beddings Store – Customer Relations/Admin, Executive JAN 2001 – DEC 2008

- Assessed customer needs, evaluated customer satisfaction and optimized customer services
- Organized and planned day-to-day activities in the store
- · Communicated with clients, fellow traders directly and resolved customer issues

EDUCATION

B.A. English & Literature in English, University of Benin, Benin Edo State, November 2014

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

New Managers Covenant Community Group - Fellow

2023

This is an online community of new leaders from various sectors navigating new managerial roles. The team and I visited "The Correctional Centre for Girls Idi Araba". We made a donation of provisions worth over 300,000 naira and I interacted with girls who are aiming to study Art courses at university level.

Women in Leadership Covenant Community Group - Fellow

2022

An 8-week online community of women leaders in different key leadership positions across various sectors.

Working Singles Covenant Community Group - Fellow

2021

An 8-week online forum for singles who are working-class individuals, studying professional courses at the same time.

University of Michigan (IN PROGRESS)

Foundational Skills for Communicating About Health

Digital Marketing Skill Institute

(IN PROGRESS)

WordPress Website Development and SEO course

02Academy Lagos

MAY 2023

Hands on school on brand communications and best copy writer award recipient

Reuters Digital Journalism Course, REUTERS

SEPT 2021

Online training for best practices in journalism

Fluent Speech Educational Consult, Lagos

APRIL 2019

Diction and Montessori Phonics Training Course

The Voice & Mind Institute, Lagos

AUG 2018

Basic On-Air Presentation Skills

UNICEF

DEC 2006

Peer Educators Training

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

The Covenant Nation Children's Teacher and Creative Instructor

2019 TILL DATE

Write presentation scripts and teach 2 – 12-year-olds to learn and make special presentations

Young African Leaders Initiative YALI Lagos Network

2021-2022

Developed and produced communication campaigns for member's projects

Street2School Initiative Tutor

2022

Taught primary 5 and 6 class literature in English and donated Literature books to both classes

CORE TVVolunteer News Reporter

2019

Nigerian Christian Corper's Fellowship NCCF Ibadan South Zone

2014 - 2015

Sister's Coordinator and welfare secretary